Austin Xu

CONTACT Information Phone: (248) 402-3571 Email: axu77@gatech.edu https://austinxu87.github.io/

RESEARCH INTERESTS Interested in preference learning, ranking to learn, and, more generally, incorporating human preferences and ranking systems into traditional machine learning fields such as reinforcement learning and generative models. Broadly interested in studying human decision making and its impacts from an interpretable and mathematically grounded perspective.

EDUCATION

Georgia Institute of Technology, Atlanta, GA

Ph.D., Electrical and Computer Engineering

Aug. 2019 – Present

Concentration: Digital Signal Processing and Machine Learning

GPA: 4.0

GPA: 3.98

Advisor: Dr. Mark Davenport

University of Michigan, Ann Arbor, MI

B.S.E, Electrical Engineering, Summa Cum Laude

Sept. 2015 – May 2019

Concentration: Digital Signal Processing

Industry Experience

Sandia National Laboratories

May 2018 - Aug. 2018

Undergraduate R&D Intern, Flight and Instrumentation Systems Group

Albuquerque, NM

- Developed features for GUI that communicates to FPGA and imaging array via SpaceWire/RMAP. Implemented modular design that incorporates hardware specific communication and file parsing. Optimized testing workflow for hardware changes, which enabled rapid future hardware prototyping. [C++, Qt Creator].
- Implemented internal image processing algorithm. Quantified algorithm accuracy under fixed point and floating point datatypes to determine hardware implementation viability. [Matlab].

General Motors

May 2017 - Aug. 2017

Student Intern, Automated Driving and Active Safety Group

Warren, MI

- Collaborated with GM and tier 1 supplier to develop and implement supply-chain-wide thermal validation plan for rear view camera coaxial cable. Validation plan was integrated for all future rear view cameras.
- Utilized internal software to de-warp rear view camera images to meet internal and government guidelines. Discovered discrepancy between test vehicle de-warping output and specifications, resulting in re-calibrated software update.

TEACHING EXPERIENCE

Graduate Teaching Assistant

Aug. 2019 - Present

Professional and Technical Communications (ECE 3005) | Georgia Institute of Technology

- Individually consulted with 20+ undergraduate students to develop their technical communication skills. Provided constructive feedback on resumes, technical documents, and presentations.
- Interfaced with students during 15 hours of weekly office hours, graded assignments, and assisted with in-class activities.

Instructional Aide

Sept. 2018 - May 2019

Discrete Mathematics (EECS 203) | University of Michigan

- Interacted with groups of 20+ undergraduate students during weekly recitation section and office hours. Effectively answered questions, explained concepts, and solved guided practice problems. Achieved an instructor evaluation of 4.7/5.0.
- Managed group of 16 graders. Created weekly grading assignments and rubrics, proofread homework solutions, and enforced grading timeline.
- Created homework and exam problems in collaboration with 18 other staff members. Half of individually created exam problems were used on exams, which was highest rate among IAs.

Conference Publications [1] A. Xu and M. A. Davenport, "Simultaneous Preference and Metric Learning from Paired Comparisons", $Submitted, \, June \, 2020$

Workshops	 Gene Golub SIAM Summer School African Institute for Mathematical Sciences (AIMS) Muizenberg, South A Selected as one of 30 global participants for the "Theory and Practice of school. Postponed to July 2021 due to COVID-19 pandemic. 	
AWARDS	President's Fellowship Georgia Institute of Technology Distinguished Academic Achievement Award University of Michigan Outstanding Service Award, EECS Dept. University of Michigan EECS Scholar University of Michigan Eta Kappa Nu Scholarship University of Michigan James B. Angell Scholar University of Michigan William J. Branstrom Freshman Prize University of Michigan Dean's List/University Honors University of Michigan	Aug. 2019 Mar. 2019 Feb. 2018 Feb. 2018 April 2017 Mar. 2017 Mar. 2016 All Semesters
SERVICE	Undergraduate Engineering Student Advisory Board (UESAB) Electrical Engineering Representative University of Michigan	Sept. 2018 - May 2019
	Eta Kappa Nu - Beta Epsilon Chapter Officer - Historian University of Michigan	Sept. 2018 - Dec. 2018
	ECE Undergraduate Advising Office Peer Advisor University of Michigan	Sept. 2017 - Dec. 2018
	STEM Society Laboratory Leader University of Michigan	Sept. 2017 - Dec 2018
	Eta Kappa Nu - Beta Epsilon Chapter Tutoring Chair University of Michigan	Jan. 2018 - May 2018